<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Homebrew-Content</name>
		<update version="1.2.0">
			<file name="Homebrew-Content.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LiberTea90/Chronos-Homebrew/master/Chronos/Homebrew-Content.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<!-- Weapons -->
	<element name="Clockwork Battleaxe" type="Magic Item" source="Chronos Homebrew" id="ID_CHRONOS_HOMEBREW_MAGIC_ITEM_CLOCKWORK_BATTLEAXE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Clock Strike</b> When you hit a creature with this weapon you can expend one charge and force them to make a Wisdom saving throw (DC 15).  On a failure the creature suffers the effects of a "Slow" spell (using your concentration).  A creature affected by the "Slow" spell in this way can repeat the saving throw at the end of its turn.  You may dismiss the effect as a Bonus Action on your turn.</p>
			<p></p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Defect:</b></p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Gear Jam</b> If the creature succeeds on their saving throw against your Clock Strike, the effect backfires.  Make a Wisdom saving throw (DC 15).  On a failure you suffer the effects of a "Slow" spell (using your concentration).  You may repeat the saving throw at the end of your next turn or dismiss the effect as a Bonus Action on your next turn.</p>
			
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="type" addition="battleaxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe</set>
			<set name="name-format">Clockwork Battleaxe</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!-- Feats -->
	<element name="Infernal Step" type="Feat" source="Chronos Homebrew" id="ID_CHRONOS_HOMEBREW_FEAT_INFERNAL_STEP">
		<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisite: DM Discretion</i></p>
			<p></p>
			<ul>
				<li>You can cast the <b><i>Misty Step</i></b> spell once per day without a spell slot.</li>
				<li>When you cast the spell using this feat all creatures within 10 feet of where you disappeared must make a Dexterity Saving throw, taking 2d6 Fire damage on a failed save or half as much on a successful one.</li>
			</ul>			
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can cast the <b><i>Misty Step</i></b> spell once per day without a spell slot.
			When you cast the spell using this feat all creatures within 10 feet of where you disappeared must make a Dexterity Saving throw, taking 2d6 Fire damage on a failed save or half as much on a successful one.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<!-- Spells -->
	 <element name="Starlight Spear" type="Spell" source="All the Lights in the Sky are Stars" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_SPELL_STARLIGHT_SPEAR">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You weave threads of starlight together to create a spear of solidified light in your hand. This magic spear lasts until the spell ends. It counts as a simple melee weapon with which you are proficient. It deals 2d12 radiant damage on a hit and has the reach and thrown (20/60ft.) properties. In addition, if you move at least 20 feet straight toward a target, your next attack with this weapon deals an additional 1d12 radiant damage on a hit.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you drop the weapon or throw it, it dissipates at the end of the turn. Thereafter, while the spell persists, you can use a bonus action to cause the spear to reappear in your hand.</p>
            <p class="indent"><em><strong>At Higher Levels.</strong></em> When you cast this spell using a 3rd- or 4th-level spell slot, the damage increases to 3d12. When you cast it using a 5th- or 6th-level spell slot, the damage increases to 4d12. When you cast it using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases to 5d12.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time"> 1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="duration"> Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range"> Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
	
</elements>
